[birds chirping]
[ethereal music playing]
[metal clanking]
[wheels rolling]
[boy laughing]
[boy, in Hindi] Faster, didi.
It's so much fun.
Faster!
Woo-hoo!
Yay!
Faster, didi. [cheering]
[upbeat music playing]
[shouting joyfully]
[laughing]
Faster!
[music fades]
[children clamoring]
[in English] Bye.
[people clamoring]
[in Hindi] Please have a look.
What can you offer for this?
Fifty rupees.
- That's too low.
- This quality doesn't sell here.
- At least have a look at the goods.
- I can’t offer you more. Please leave.
[soft instrumental music playing]
[students laughing]
[students clamoring]
You're still missing school?
Uh...
Well, sir...
She was busy at home.
I'll send her tomorrow.
- [teacher] Sure?
- Yes, sir.
Okay, see you tomorrow.
- Didi?
- Hmm?
What are you doing?
I can go to school tomorrow,
but I've outgrown my uniform.
[indistinct chattering]
[dog barking]
Didi, take this.
What's this?
I got you a uniform.
Where did you get this from?
And it's white!
At least you have a uniform now.
[students, in English] Good morning, sir.
[teacher] Good morning.
[in Hindi] Sit down.
All right, kids,
today we’ll study chapter three
and learn about water resources.
I'll be talking
about the key water problems.
Listen carefully.
- Where's your book?
- [teacher] First is the scarcity of water.
Exploitation of groundwater.
Inability to use surface water.
Overuse of agricultural land.
You there!
Stand up.
Where's your textbook?
I forgot.
You've finally come to school,
and you forgot your textbook?
And what's up with your uniform?
Go.
Clean the corridors.
Move!
[students laugh]
[teacher] Silence!
[girl]
Sir, I need a token for the computer room.
[teacher] Hmm. Go.
[girl, in English] Thank you.
[computer keys clacking]
[in Hindi] What did you do?
Hmm?
I forgot my textbook.
- [people clamoring]
- [horns honking]
[bus conductor] Going to Khempur.
Come on, everyone. Khempur!
All aboard. Going to Khempur.
Khempur!
Going to Khempur!
[soulful music playing]
KHEMPUR
6 KM
[Hindi song playing on radio]
[man] Time to get off.
- Huh?
- Get down.
Here?
What? No...
I need to go here.
To Vikram Ji’s... It’s a hotel.
[scoffs]
[sighs]
[soft piano music playing]
[grunts]
[sighs]
- Uh, Vikram?
- [in English] Welcome, ma'am.
- [in Hindi] Please come.
- [in English] Thank you.
[Vikram, in Hindi] This is your room.
Ever since I've listed online,
I’ve got an incredible response.
I get bookings from around the world.
Just like you've come from London.
How many nights is your booking for?
[in English] I'm just here for two weeks.
[Vikram] Oh. No issues.
[in Hindi] You will have no complaints.
But give us a good review when you leave.
Ma’am, the view here is our specialty.
People come from all over
just for this view.
It’s a beautiful sight.
Get some rest. Good night.
[woman, in English] Thank you.
[woman, in Hindi]
This month's repayments are due.
[man] Okay. Give me lentils.
I was thinking... I mean...
Rupa was saying that
she's filled the local form
to start stitching.
If you don't have any objection,
- I...
- Do you think I'm incapable?
Working in the brick kiln isn't that bad.
You working in the fields is enough.
[woman] But it's not enough
to run the house.
We’ll be in further debt.
- Maybe I could help as well.
- [man] Oh, really?
So will you both run the house?
You can barely sell peanuts,
and you want to help?
- And that's why I want to...
- [man] I, what?
Do you know what people will say
if you work outside in a factory?
That I'm incapable to run my house,
and I'm making my wife work.
No, but I mean,
times are changing.
[plate clangs]
[man] What an expert!
More rice?
20 RUPEES
One bottled water, please.
- How much?
- Twenty rupees.
[in English] Thank you.
[man, in Hindi] Want the textbook too?
No, I'll buy it later.
Okay.
[in English] Hi.
[in Hindi]
Is there anything to see around?
Yes. The village.
[chuckles softly]
- [children laughing and shouting]
- [upbeat music playing]
[girl] Ankush! What are you doing?
Ankush, come here!
Ankush! Leave him, Ankush!
What are you doing, Ankush? Let him go!
No, Ankush!
What’s this nonsense, Ankush?
Are you out of your mind?
He started it
by calling me a toilet cleaner.
[boy] That's true.
He got toilet-duty in school today,
but he ran away.
You're no elite.
You are a toilet cleaner too.
Everyone knows you failed twice in school.
[children laugh]
- Should I tell her what you did?
- [Ankush] Let’s go, didi.
- Should I tell her?
- Didi, he's cooking up stories.
Toilet cleaner is running away.
See that filthy rat run.
Look at that toilet cleaner.
[children laughing and shouting]
[boy 1] Hit him!
[exclaims]
[gasping]
[screams]
[huffs]
- [boy 2] Run, Tipu!
- [girl] Didi!
[Tipu] Ankush! Wait, Ankush!
- [boy 2] Tipu, run.
Didi, sorry.
Sorry, didi.
Didi.
Didi, no.
This one isn't for us. Come with me.
That's for the upper caste.
We can use this one.
[woman sighs]
[in English] Sorry, didi.
[chuckles] It's okay.
[girl, in Hindi] What's your name?
Uh, Jessica.
- And yours?
- Prerna.
Where are you from?
Uh, London.
- London?
- Yes.
But my dad was from India.
What are you doing here?
[laughs softly]
Are you married?
[laughs softly] Nope.
How old are you?
[in English] Thirty four.
[in Hindi] And you're still not married?
[clicks tongue]
My friend has
a one-year-old daughter already.
How old are you?
Okay, what grade are you in?
Tell me.
I don't go to school anymore.
Why not?
I don't have a school uniform.
That’s it?
Because of a school uniform?
So what do you do then?
Housework, work in the fields
and in the market.
But it's important to go to school.
If you don't go to school,
what will you do in the future?
[wheels rolling]
[shouting playfully]
- [in English] Sorry, auntie.
- [Jessica] You little brat.
[in Hindi] Look at my hair and my shirt.
- [in Hindi] You can speak in Hindi?
- Yes.
What's this?
His bearing car.
Come, take a look.
This is my bearing car.
[Jessica laughs]
[in English]
Oh my God. Just like a skateboard.
- [in Hindi] Did you make it?
- Yes.
Skateboard?
You don't know what’s a skateboard?
Okay, give me a minute.
[in English] Ugh! No connection.
[in Hindi] Try it, come on.
- Come.
- Oh no.
- Come on.
- Try it, it will be fun.
Come.
[Jessica laughs]
[wheels rolling]
- [Ankush laughing]
- [Jessica cheering]
- [Jessica] Now, you do it.
- [Ankush] See, it was fun, right?
[Ankush] Slow down.
Listen, where does one get new uniforms?
[Ankush laughing in video]
See, it was fun, right?
[mobile phone notifications dinging]
[in Hindi]
I thought she'd yell or even hit me.
- But she didn't.
- [mother chuckles]
She was very polite.
And then...
I don't know why.
...she spoke about herself.
Asked me what I do.
She’s very sweet.
She's a foreigner
but speaks Hindi really well.
- She also sprays perfume on her hands.
- [laughing]
But what is she doing here?
I don't know.
She doesn't know either.
- Where is she from?
- London.
London? Where's this village?
[Prerna sighs softly]
[clicks tongue] It's brand new.
And she didn't want anything in return?
There's got to be a reason.
[tuts] You're so silly,
taking stuff from strangers.
Don't let your father see this, hmm?
Go now.
Prerna.
The textbook.
- What are you studying?
- The map.
[goat bleating]
[bleating continues]
[bleats]
- [priest chanting]
- [bell ringing]
Ankush.
[chanting continues]
- Where did you get him from?
- He is...
Gillu.
You goat thief! Did you steal a goat?
Look, Ma, she stole a goat.
Ma, he was trapped over there.
I just saved his life.
That's good. Now leave him here.
It belongs to someone else.
He's a stray.
Can’t we take him home?
[mother] No way!
[soft instrumental music playing]
[Ankush] Do you know
what I prayed for in the temple?
[Prerna] What?
See this.
- Cool shoes, right?
- Keep dreaming.
What did you pray for?
Never mind. God can't hear you
from outside the temple.
Why didn't you come inside?
Stomach cramps.
Again?
Shut up, Ankush.
[children, in English] Wow! Wow!
[in English] There.
[in Hindi]
My bearing car looks awesome, no?
[children] Yes!
How do I get it out?
- [chuckles] You want it?
- Yes.
Okay, give it to me. I'll draw it for you.
[children gasp] Whoa!
[boy 1] Didi, draw my tractor too.
- I have a DJ car!
- My rolling cart!
- [boy 2] I have a water tanker.
- Okay.
[children clamoring]
[in English] Okay, I'll draw all of yours.
Everybody get into a line.
[soulful music plays]
[Ankush, in Hindi] It's lovely, isn’t it?
[in English] Thank you.
Hi. You want to come?
[in Hindi] He won’t come.
Why?
He's from the upper caste.
[woman] What are you doing here?
How many times have I told you
to not play with these kids? Let's go.
[in English] There.
[Jessica humming]
[in Hindi] Here you go. I got it out.
- [in English] Thank you.
- [laughs]
Okay. Next!
[upbeat music playing]
- [horn honking]
- [Ankush, in Hindi] Bearing car!
- [children clamoring]
- [man] Whoa!
[man laughs] Whoa!
- [children clamoring]
- [in English] Hey! Hey! Hey!
What's this? What's this?
[in Hindi] My bearing car!
[Jessica laughs] Erick!
[in English] What are you doing here?
Come on! I mean,
I had to come to see this thing.
See how cool it is? [laughs]
[in Hindi] Ma'am, he was asking
about you in the entire village,
so I brought him here directly. Who is he?
[in English] This is my friend from LA.
Are you... Are you still teaching here?
I'm sorry.
I'm just so surprised right now.
[in Hindi]
Didi, his bearing car is so nice.
This is a skateboard.
- Skateboard?
[Jessica] Mm-hmm.
[in English]
Hello, brother, wash-your-name?
Hey, first wash your face!
[chuckles] I'm, uh... I'm... I'm Erick.
[in Hindi] And your names?
[in English] Prerna.
Meaning "inspiration."
I am Ankush. I am... Meaning...
- I don't know.
- That's still cool.
- Bhaiya, I am Tipu.
- I am Rahul.
[children clamoring]
[in Hindi] Hey, Tipya, leave him alone.
[in English] Don’t disturb bhaiya.
No, it's cool.
- [in Hindi] Bhaiya, please skate for us.
- Please, bhaiya. Show us. Just once!
[in English] They want you to show them
something fun on your board.
I... I can do that. I'm just gonna...
Okay. Well.
[children] Oh! Whoa!
[Jessica] Whoo!
[children clapping]
[children cheer]
- [boy 1] That's awesome!
- [boy 2] He's fast!
[boy 3] Look, he was in mid-air.
[children] Whoa!
They are so good.
Do you want to try it?
No. I won't be able to do it.
Just try and step on the board once.
No, didi, I'll fall.
Didi, you won't.
Try it. It will be fun.
[boy 4] Didi, try it. You’ll enjoy.
[in English] Okay.
[inspirational music playing]
[music builds]
[Prerna gasps]
- [children laugh]
- Oi, guys!
[in Hindi]
I told you, I won't be able to do it.
[Jessica, in English]
Come on! Don't give up.
Miss Inspiration.
[in Hindi]
That's what your name means, right?
[in English] You've got it.
Okay.
This way around.
Come on.
Okay.
[inspirational music playing]
[children cheering and applauding]
[Ankush, in Hindi]
I told you my didi could do it.
[ethereal music playing]
- [crowd applauding]
- [Jessica, in English] Yes, Prerna!
[in Hindi] Now show them how to do it.
- [boy 1] I'll also try it.
- [Ankush] I will go after you.
[boy 2] And me too!
[Prerna]
Bhaiya, will I get to skate again?
[Ankush] Bhaiya, will you come tomorrow?
[children] Please, bhaiya!
Hey! What? Quiet!
- Bhaiya, please.
[in English] Do you wanna stay
and teach them some skateboarding?
I'd love to,
but I'd have to get covered at the school.
Wait. Wait. Wait.
How... how long are you here for?
Did Sid fire you or something?
No. He let me have two weeks off.
[in Hindi]
Bhaiya, I want to skate again. Please.
[in English] I can arrange
another room for you. No issues.
[in Hindi] Bhaiya, please stay back.
[in English] How am I supposed to say no
to this? I mean... Yeah, I'm staying.
[children cheering]
[soft instrumental music playing]
[in Hindi] Get me my book.
[girl] What do you want?
Prerna.
Do you want to use the computer?
Do you know how to go online?
Yes. Wait. I'll show you.
[Prerna] I want to see skating videos.
- [banging]
- [children shouting]
[in English] Into the hips,
and you just lift up the feet.
It's like the sea. [whooshes]
Hold on to this.
You can practice and give it back.
[in Hindi] Can I keep it for now?
[in English] Yeah.
- Thank you.
- It's fine.
[soft instrumental music playing]
[in Hindi] Where did this come from?
Someone gave it to Ankush for a day.
I will return it tomorrow.
Why are you playing
with things meant for boys?
Go, cook some lentils.
[laughing]
What's going on?
Get back to class.
Go.
[in English] Sorry, Papa.
[in Hindi]
Don't lower your standards. Got it?
Yes, Papa.
Go on.
[Prerna] Ankush, look.
I’m flying!
[laughs]
- [shouts]
- Didi, careful!
[board splashes in water]
The board's gone.
[Prerna panting]
[Ankush] Didi!
Didi!
Who asked you to dive in?
You’ve ruined Erick Bhaiya's board.
How will we explain this at home?
Had fun skating?
Come, Gillu.
[mother] What did I tell you earlier?
You took something from a stranger again?
[motorbike approaches, stops]
[whispering] Go, hide it now. And listen,
you better return it first thing tomorrow.
Go quickly.
Kamlesh has put me
on double shifts starting tomorrow.
- [mother] Water?
- No.
[bills rustling]
[Jessica, in English] It's so different
to London. It's so peaceful here.
[Vikram, in Hindi] Get down.
[Erick, in English]
It's Miss Inspiration herself.
[Jessica] What... what's happened?
[in Hindi] What happened?
Skateboard!
[in Hindi] What?
How much does a skateboard cost?
She's ruined Erick Bhaiya's skateboard.
It's destroyed.
Sorry, bhaiya.
[Jessica gasps, laughs]
[Prerna, in English] Very sorry.
How did you even do this?
Oh man! [chuckles]
[Jessica] Um...
Sorry, bhaiya.
Did you go surfing, huh? [whooshes]
[Jessica laughs]
[Prerna] Bhaiya!
- No.
- Please, bhaiya.
No. I don't need it. I don't want it.
This is... It's okay.
[Jessica, in Hindi]
Come on, now go to school.
[Erick, in English] Hey.
It's okay. I don't mind.
[Jessica] Oh no.
[father, in Hindi]
Stealing in your own house?
Is this what we’ve taught you?
No, Papa. I...
I was putting it back.
So, you did steal before?
I’m asking you something.
I made a mistake, Papa.
Didi.
Why did you put the money back?
We could’ve bought chocolates with it.
We could’ve had so much fun.
[in English] Sorry.
It's cool. I will finish that off.
- Hi, guys.
- [children] Hi, didi.
[Jessica] I have a small surprise.
You didn't?
- No way.
- I couldn't resist.
Want to see what's inside?
[children, in Hindi] Yes!
[Ankush]
This is a real bearing car, right?
[children] Wow! Whoa!
[children chattering]
[Vikram] Subodh.
[in English] This one's for you.
[in Hindi] No.
[in English] It's for you. Please.
- [in Hindi] For me?
- Yes.
[in English] Take it.
[Erick] No way.
- Yours got ruined. So, I just...
- [Erick] Thank you.
Didi.
[in Hindi] Do you think
she will get us new shoes too?
No?
[in English] Perfect.
Thanks so much for sticking around.
Couldn't have done it without you.
You kidding?
You think I'd have missed this?
This is huge.
I mean, this doesn't happen every day.
You just gave these kids
their first board. [laughs softly]
Do you remember your first board?
[Erick] Yeah. I do.
Um, I was eight years old,
and my mom bought it for me.
Pretty much saved my life.
[Jessica] What do you mean?
Uh...
I mean, my mom got it
to keep me out of the house.
Because my stepdad was...
[breathes deeply]
He wasn't a nice person.
I'm sorry.
It's cool.
So, are you gonna tell me why you're here?
[chuckling] Come on, Jess.
You do not take time off work,
and I haven't seen you visiting
any relatives. So...
Why are you in this village?
[Jessica]
The little boy in the picture is my dad.
He was adopted from this village
when he was seven.
I just found out a few weeks ago
when my granddad gave me the picture.
How did they even meet?
My granddad used to own
a factory around here,
you know, back in the day.
And one night there was a fire,
and one of his workers
got trapped inside the building.
And before anyone could help,
he passed away.
When my granddad went to the funeral,
he met the only family of that worker,
his seven-year-old son,
my dad.
That's incredible.
Yeah. It is incredible how one small step
can just completely change
the course of someone's life.
I mean, if it wasn't for my granddad,
my dad would've spent
his whole life in this village.
He wouldn't have ever met my mom.
I wouldn't even be here.
How do you feel about that?
I wish he had told me
when he was still alive.
But...
But I knew that I needed
to come to this village,
and just be here,
and see where he grew up.
And, you know, meeting all these kids,
it just...
It makes me feel like I'm close to him.
You told anyone in the village?
No, I don't want to disrupt anything here.
[chuckles]
What?
You just gave those kids skateboards.
You have disrupted everything.
[kids cheering]
[upbeat music playing]
[cyclist shouts]
[boy shouts]
[man, in Hindi] Hey!
Hey, get out!
[Ankush]
Wow, didi, you're doing it so well.
- [in English] Good morning, sir.
- Good morning.
- [in Hindi] Where is everyone else?
- Skating.
[man 1] They've disrupted everything!
Sir, we need your support
to get rid of this problem.
- [man 2] Very true.
- [man 3] He's right.
- Take action.
- [man 4] I'll be out of business.
[soft instrumental music playing]
It was fun skipping school today.
FINE FOR SKATEBOARDING - RS. 500
Five-hundred rupees fine.
BEWARE OF DOGS AND DON'T SKATE HERE.
Stop! What are you doing?
Read that board.
SKATEBOARDING NOT ALLOWED.
[teacher] Today we'll study
about the Father of our Nation,
Mahatma Gandhi,
who led India’s struggle
for independence with non-violence.
Gandhi’s Dandi March, Quit India Movement,
and Salt Tax Revolution
caused an outbreak in the nation.
Skating is not a crime.
Not a crime, not a crime.
[Ankush] We kids want to shine.
[children chanting]
Want to shine, want to shine.
Fulfill our wishes now!
Fulfill them now, fulfill them now.
[Ankush] Skating is not a crime.
[children chanting]
Not a crime, not a crime.
We kids want to shine.
Want to shine, want to shine.
Fulfill our wishes now!
Fulfill them now, fulfill them now.
[Ankush] Skating is not a crime.
Look! It’s the teacher! Run!
[upbeat music playing]
Now it’s an everyday nuisance.
Excuse me, you can’t confiscate
their boards like this.
Madam, there’s a complaint against you.
[scoffs] What is their crime?
There were only two students
in my class today, thanks to you!
The regular ones are skipping school, too,
because of this nuisance.
And these brats are influencing
my son too!
[in English] Okay, look,
the last thing I want is for them
not to go to school.
Please understand. I'm just...
[in Hindi] Do you have a permit?
[in English] Permit?
[in Hindi] This is India!
Things work differently here.
Show me your Aadhaar card.
[in English] I don't have one.
[in Hindi] It’s mandatory.
[in English] I'm a British citizen.
- [in Hindi] Show me your passport.
- [scoffs]
This is the root cause of the problem.
- Just hear me out, please...
- Listen to me, madam.
You’re still an Indian, aren’t you?
Yes, do you doubt it?
Then why bring these Western things here?
[in English]
They're kids. They're having fun.
They're playing, learning a sport.
These kids can't be skating like that
in the middle of the streets.
[in Hindi] They start skating anywhere,
from shops and alleys
to places
where they aren't even allowed to enter.
They've created chaos
in the whole village.
Look, madam, we have a system here.
There are rules.
They’re ruining public property.
It's not a garden or a park.
Vikram, she’s your guest and a lady,
so I’m letting her go.
- Yes.
- If I get one more complaint...
[in English]
I’ll have to take serious action.
- [in Hindi] It won't happen again.
- [police officer] You can go.
[quietly] Singh Sahab, take it in writing,
or they’ll do it again.
Listen, if any of you
miss school tomorrow then...
[in English] I won't let that happen.
I'll make sure they're there tomorrow.
Guys!
[Erick sighs heavily]
Doesn't matter where you go in the world,
everybody hates skateboards.
[somber music playing]
[sentimental music playing]
[Prerna] Didi!
[in Hindi] What are you doing here?
This is the upper caste locality.
Do people still follow the caste system?
Nobody talks about it,
but it's an unsaid norm.
I am sorry that you can’t skate anymore.
[in English] I thought... I mean, I...
Those boards were a waste.
[in Hindi] Skating is
the best thing that happened to me.
How long are you here for?
I leave tomorrow.
But there’s still so much to see here.
[in English] Sit.
It's okay.
Sit.
[soft instrumental music playing]
[Erick] You been here all night?
You know, people don't hate skaters.
They hate their spirit.
I've been researching all night,
and there is no skate park in Rajasthan.
Okay.
[chuckles]
[Jessica] Skateboarding is just
in a few places in India.
- It's just picking up.
- [Erick] Yeah, I know.
- Uh, let me get this straight. You want...
- I wanna build a skate park.
[laughs]
- [Vikram] Skate park?
- Yeah.
- [in Hindi] In this village?
- [Jessica] Yes.
[in English]
Do you have this kind of money?
Uh, I actually just gave up
a huge promotion at work, so no.
But I really need to do this.
[Vikram]
It'll be a huge tourist attraction.
- Exactly.
- I am with you, ma'am. No issues.
Thank you, Vikram. And you?
- I'm going to Bangalore.
- What?
[in Hindi] Hey. Hey, bhai.
[in English]
If you go, who's going to help us?
Well, see,
if we're gonna build a skate park,
we're gonna need a team,
and my guy is in Bangalore.
[exclaims]
[chuckles]
Yes! We're doing it!
Thank you.
Thank you, Vikram. Wow.
We're building a skate park.
[children] "No school. No skateboarding."
Yay! No school! Yay!
- [in Hindi] Tipya, no school.
- No!
Ankush, no.
This means if you don’t go to school,
you won’t be allowed to skate.
- What?
- [Jessica] Yes.
[in English] It’s a rule.
[in Hindi]
They come up with new rules every day.
[children, in English] Good morning, sir.
Good morning.
[in Hindi] Sit down.
Hmm.
- [in English] Nice.
- Thank you.
Big goals. Very nice.
[in Hindi]
No one has ever thought this way before.
[in English] Very nice. Very nice.
Who is actually involved?
Your father? Husband?
Um, no, it's just me.
- [in Hindi] Alone?
- Hmm.
[in English] Very nice. Very nice.
With funds sanctioned from the government,
we can make
an international-standard skate park.
That is very expensive, madam.
[in Hindi]
How can I sanction that kind of money?
Our charity funds
have already been allotted for this year.
Besides, you’re not from an official NGO.
Try next year.
[in English] After registration. Promise.
[in Hindi] And if you need any other help,
let me know. Hmm?
- [in English] Actually...
- Your minister is here to help you. Hmm?
Always.
[in Hindi] We can’t justify these funds.
This game...
I mean sport.
It has no rules.
How can I propose a sport
with no rules to the committee?
The Sports Association
won't be able to help you.
Why don’t you try
for private or personal funding?
[in English]
I'll do that. Thank you. Let's go.
None of these guys are gonna help us.
There is nothing in it for them.
Ma'am, they don't understand
why you are doing this.
We need a higher up connection
to get things done here.
Namaste.
I heard about your project.
No one has ever dared
to ask my land before.
I know it's a really big ask.
[in Hindi] Why do you want to build
this skate park in that village?
I was raised in London.
I knew what I wanted to be
while I was still in school.
[in English] When I asked
one of the girls in the village...
[in Hindi]
"What do you want to do when you grow up?"
She had no answer.
Because no one
had ever asked her that before.
[in English] It crushed me.
They are so wonderful
and creative with the little they have.
And I look at them,
and I wonder if we would discover
a scientist, or a musician, you know,
or the next pro-skater
right here in this village
if we just give them a platform
and someone to believe in them.
And I don't know why,
but skating strikes a chord with them.
I know a girl who says
that when she skates, she feels free.
For the first time, she's allowed herself
to dream, you know, and that inspires me.
Now, boys and girls from different castes,
who would never even usually mingle,
are now all skating together.
I mean, if we don't give
these girls a chance, then who will?
[woman] Please give me a moment.
[chair moving]
[footsteps receding]
[in Hindi]
I was thinking about what you said.
People resist change here,
especially if that change
is led by a woman.
There are unsaid rules for women here,
some of which you’ve already broken.
If I deny you today,
life will go on as is.
But if I say yes,
maybe we’ll see a better tomorrow?
And it could give several girls
the courage to follow their dreams.
[sniffles]
Someday I’ll tell you my story.
But for now, start your work.
[in English] All the best.
[sighs, sniffles]
- Thank you.
- All the best.
[in Hindi] No one can stop us now.
[in English]
I can't believe this is finally happening.
[in Hindi] Ma’am,
I'll sort everything out.
[people cheering]
Wow.
[Erick, in English] Well, here they are,
your world-class team.
- Janthavy.
- Hi.
- [Jessica] Hi!
- Jacob.
- Nice to meet you.
- Kevin.
- Atita. Mikkjel.
- Hello! I'm Jacob.
- Welcome to India.
- Thank you.
- I'm Jessica.
- I'm Mikkjel.
- Hi.
- Abhishek.
- Welcome to India.
- Thank you.
- Man, I'm from Bangalore.
No issues, sir. Welcome to Rajasthan.
Yeah. Thank you.
Okay, guys, I...
Uh, thank you so much for being here
and for helping us
with this crazy passion project.
Um, we've been through so much
to get to this point,
and it's just awesome
that you guys are here to help us.
Thank you so much for having us.
We're so stoked to be here right now.
[man] So where are we gonna build this?
So, this is going to be
Rajasthan's first-ever skate park.
- We are gonna completely transform it.
- Let's do it.
[instrumental music playing]
[inaudible]
[music builds]
[man vocalizing in Hindi]
[music fades]
[in Hindi] Tea, please.
[phone ringing]
Whose call are you avoiding?
Bhawani Ji's.
He wants to get involved now
because the elections are nearing.
[in English] I know what he can do for us.
Ankush.
[in Hindi] What's up?
[in English] Skating championship.
[in Hindi] Let’s go.
Let's go, everyone. Hurry up.
- Jessica ma'am is calling us.
- Come on, fast.
[children shouting joyfully]
[in English] Hi!
[children cheering]
[boy, in Hindi]
Wow. Look how good they are at it.
You all have three months to practice.
[in English] And there's gonna be skaters
coming from all over India.
So, you're gonna need to practice up
for a 45-second run.
[children murmuring]
And you're gonna need
to say this to them in Hindi.
Yeah.
[in Hindi] Skaters from all over India
will participate in the contest.
You will each get a 45-second run,
and you have to showcase
as many tricks as you can.
What do you mean by tricks?
Just like an ollie,
do as many tricks as you know.
What if we fall? Are we done?
No, you get back on the board.
A whistle will blow
after 45 seconds are over,
which means your time is up.
But remember, you also get points
to skate till the very end.
[in English] Okay?
And you will be getting points for tricks,
but it's about style and power too.
Yeah?
I think you guys
should get in there and practice.
Come on! Let's go skate!
[children cheering]
[in Hindi] Hey, move, move aside!
[n English] They look petrified.
Yeah. They are petrified, but that's okay.
Because this is completely different
to anything they've ever done before.
Come on. You wanna try?
[in Hindi] No, you go ahead.
[in English] You wanna push down so hard
that it's going through the floor
and then release.
Pop!
Slide it forward
and slam it down in landing.
That's an ollie.
- Ollie?
- That's it.
["Shine On Me" playing]
[in Hindi] ♪ I've touched the pinnacle
I've realized my worth ♪
♪ Now that my feet
Have opened up as wings... ♪
Hey, guys. Do you want to see a drop in?
[children, in Hindi] Yes.
[in English] Yeah?
♪ Why shouldn't I weave
The dreams my eyes have seen? ♪
[children] Wow.
♪ My complicated life
I have to resolve ♪
♪ The trust I have in me has to manifest ♪
♪ I’ll touch the sky, immersed in joy... ♪
[Erick] Yeah, Ankush!
That kid has no fear.
[in English]
♪ There's no other feeling like this ♪
♪ Oh, my feet on the ground ♪
♪ I've been searching for an answer ♪
♪ One that I think I've found ♪
You can do it, Prerna.
♪ Reaching for the sky
Every time I fall, I get back up ♪
♪ If I never try
How will I know what I'm made of? ♪
♪ There will be a time
When the sun will shine ♪
♪ Feels like today ♪
♪ Oh, oh... ♪
[woman] Wow!
[giggles]
[in Hindi] Are you having fun, Kusum?
[in Hindi] ♪ I've taken flight ♪
♪ Whoa oh, whoa oh, oh hoh ♪
[in English]
♪ I know sun is gonna shine on me ♪
♪ Oh ♪
[in Hindi] ♪ Following my heart ♪
♪ In spite of the fear ♪
♪ Riding on these wheels... ♪
- [laughs]
- Didi!
- [cheers]
Oh.
[in English] You did it.
♪ If I never try it, I will never know ♪
♪ And I can't give up on my dreams, yeah ♪
♪ So I'mma bring the light, yeah
I'mma start a fire ♪
♪ I'm not afraid, I am free ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ No ♪
♪ Sun is gonna, sun is gonna shine on me ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Oh, whoa-oh ♪
♪ Sun is, sun is gonna shine on me ♪
[in Hindi] ♪ I've taken flight ♪
[song ends]
[chattering indistinctly]
- [boy 1] Bye.
- [man 1] Bye.
[man 2] See you. Ciao.
- [Jessica] Appreciate it.
- [boy 2] Bye.
[children] Bye.
[all cheering and shouting]
Ankush.
[Ankush groans]
[Ankush] Huh?
[in Hindi] Get up.
[Ankush] Hmm?
How did you manage to drop in
at the first attempt?
Weren't you scared of falling?
I was,
but I did it anyway.
We're working so hard
for this contest. Aren’t we?
[Prerna] Hmm.
[inspirational music playing]
[music fades]
[Ankush] And now, presenting
the number one skater of this village,
Prerna Bhil.
Today she's going to show us
the biggest drop in!
Didi, just do it.
[breathing heavily]
[soft instrumental music playing]
Didi!
Didi.
Are you okay?
[Tipu] Ankush. Come!
[Ankush] I’ll be back soon.
Tipya, wait for me.
[mother] What did you break?
[Prerna cries]
What are you doing?
Let me see it.
How did this happen?
It's just a bruise.
But how did this happen?
[wincing]
I fell while skating.
You’ve created a nuisance in the village.
Keep my daughter out of it.
[in English] Sorry.
[in Hindi] What happened?
What have you been teaching Prerna?
To lie and steal?
To behave like a boy?
She can't even do her housework.
She's at home with a swollen foot.
[scoffs]
[Jessica]
She must have hurt herself while skating.
I don't know.
But is she okay?
[father] Okay?
She should be married by now,
but she's skating.
What if something goes wrong?
Who will marry her
if she breaks her bones?
[in English] What's going on?
I literally have no idea
what he's talking about.
[in Hindi]
I can't have her follow in your footsteps.
Living-in with a man before marriage...
[in English] Excuse me! How dare you?
[in Hindi]
Madam, news travels fast in the village.
This is not your city. It's a village.
Stay away from my children!
[in English] Thank you.
[father, in Hindi] Come.
[Erick, in English]
See you later, Ankush. See you, buddy.
[Jessica] Maybe he's right.
I mean, do I really know
what's best for them?
I would've never forgiven myself
if anything worse
would've happened to her.
[sighs]
Getting injured is just
a part of skateboarding.
I know. He was just so angry.
I am an outsider.
Maybe I should just stop interfering
in their lives.
Something like this was bound to happen.
[in Hindi]
Sorry about what Papa said the other day.
[sighs]
How’s Prerna?
She's better,
but she's grounded.
She's not allowed to skate.
Why do you like skating so much?
[ethereal music playing]
I don’t know...
but it feels good.
I feel like I belong.
Like it's something I can do.
There’s no one to control me,
no rules to follow.
It feels like I'm gliding in the sky.
[ethereal music continues]
[girl]
Prerna Didi is here. Prerna Didi is here.
Come. Why didn't you come
for so many days? What happened?
Come.
[girl] Let's go. Skate.
["Maari Chhalangein" playing]
[in Hindi]
♪ As if destiny was upset with me ♪
♪ As if my hopes were broken ♪
♪ But now the whole sky is mine... ♪
[in English] You know, the only way
to conquer fear is to just go through it.
Just attack it.
[in Hindi] I can’t do it.
And what if I fall again?
♪ Let the tight fists open... ♪
[in English] Believe.
[inaudible]
[in Hindi]
♪ Now that the whole sky is mine ♪
♪ A few desires that I have ♪
♪ Should get fulfilled ♪
♪ I’ve broken the shackles
Of envy, bondage and... ♪
♪ I've taken the leap ♪
♪ Let's have a little fun ♪
♪ Now that I'm on my way ♪
♪ To turn the wheels of my life ♪
♪ I've taken the leap... ♪
You are my best friend.
Do you know who else are my best friends?
Jessica Didi and Subodh.
[inaudible]
[man vocalizing]
[woman singing]
♪ I am faster than the wind ♪
♪ I'm surprised myself ♪
♪ At the story of my life ♪
♪ The bird has broken the cage
And taken flight ♪
♪ From every worry and fear
She's turned away ♪
♪ Flown away... ♪
♪ I've taken the leap ♪
♪ Let's have a little fun ♪
♪ Now that I'm on my way ♪
♪ To turn the wheels of my life ♪
♪ I've taken the leap ♪
[song fades]
[Prerna]
"Today is the last day of the carnival."
"If you come with me,
I'll know you like me too."
[soft instrumental music playing]
[inaudible]
[father] The entire village knows
who you were with.
They are upper caste Brahmins.
We can't mingle with them.
So this is what you've been hiding.
You have got some nerve.
Injuring your foot wasn't enough?
Papa, my contest is next week.
Shut up!
- Please don't do this.
- Step back!
[Prerna cries]
[father] If you can't make us proud,
at least don't bring us shame.
[Prerna wailing]
[crowd murmuring]
Papa...
[Prerna crying]
[father] It's time to find her a groom.
I can't handle her responsibility anymore.
[Prerna crying]
Where's Gillu?
What did you do to him?
Ankush will bring her back.
[Prerna sobbing]
Hmm.
Pretty, isn't it?
- I'll take this one.
- [man] Okay.
That...
Okay.
- [man] It'll be ready in two days.
- Okay.
Be happy.
Hmm.
Let's go.
[chattering indistinctly]
Didi, if you don't like him,
don't marry him. Who cares?
At least you’ve got a new dress.
[Prerna] Ankush.
[father] After you.
- Will everything be ready in one week?
- Yes, we'll manage.
Tea?
- So what all are you good at?
- Skating.
- [woman] What?
- Setting!
- She sets the house very well.
- Okay.
- She cleans really well.
- [woman] Okay.
She even cooks very well.
She can handle all the housework.
She won't give you a reason to complain.
[woman] Okay.
- Girl looks good.
- Yes.
Yes, let's talk.
We like the girl.
You take care of the rest.
- Will you really be ready in seven days?
- Everything will be ready. Don't worry.
I have spoken to my boss.
He'll help me out too.
Why didn't you tell me before?
I’ll speak to your father.
No.
[sniffles]
Things will get complicated, didi.
He sold everything to organize this.
[sniffs]
[in English]
But this is just such a big step.
Are you sure?
[in Hindi] I only came to say goodbye.
I'll move to another village
after the wedding.
[Jessica gasps softly]
[sobs]
[both crying]
[melancholy music playing]
Prerna, what's all this?
[Prerna] Can't you see?
There's nothing more important
to you than skating, right?
It doesn't matter anymore.
There’s still time for the championship.
You can participate.
I'm getting married that same day.
Please leave, Subodh.
If someone spots you here,
all hell will break loose.
[sighs deeply]
- [folk music playing]
- [people singing]
[mother] Here, take this.
Okay.
Hey! Narayan, what are you doing here?
It's not for you to sit.
Go, give this to Dal Ji.
He's still at it.
Bhaiya, please hurry.
We've to send it there too. Hurry up.
Chanda, take this. Quick.
I'll bring another stack.
[Vikram, over PA system]
Ladies and gentlemen,
people of Khempur,
we welcome you to our
All India Skateboarding Championship!
[crowd cheers]
[Vikram] So with a huge round of applause,
let's welcome Bhawani Ji...
[crowd applauds]
...along with our two judges,
Mr. Darius and Mr. Emmanuel.
- [in English] You guys ready?
- [in Hindi] Yes!
[in English] Yeah. You're gonna be great.
All of you. Yeah!
[Vikram, in Hindi] Without further ado,
let's kick-start this championship.
Our first participant
is the pride of Khempur,
our very own, Lila!
[mother] Four boxes are right there.
Give me your hand.
Ma, Ankush said he chews tobacco.
You will soon get used to it.
Do you think he's good for me?
I hadn't even seen your father
before our wedding.
I was about your age when I got married.
I was very weak,
but you’re not.
What do you mean?
I bled a lot when you were born.
The doctor said I had a weak uterus
and had to be careful.
That's why you were premature by a month,
but girls born in the eighth month
have a fighting spirit.
That’s why you’re here today.
Weren’t you weak when Ankush was born?
I was, but a girl child isn't enough
to complete a family.
Everyone wants a son.
Besides, my choice never mattered.
Everyone has their own destiny.
No one can change that. Huh?
What if skating is my destiny?
You look beautiful.
[Vikram]
And Tipu is showcasing his unique trick.
What a great job, Tipu. Well done!
He is fearlessly moving ahead,
but uh-oh!
And that’s the end of Tipu’s 45 seconds.
And now in the Juniors' category,
from Bhil Basti, we have,
Ankush!
[crowd cheers]
[Vikram] Let's hear it for him.
Looks like he is going to start
with a trick on the ledge.
[upbeat music playing]
- Good job!
- [crowd cheers]
[in English] Come on, Ankush.
[in Hindi]
There’s something about his style.
Give him a round of applause.
Well done, Ankush!
[crowd cheers]
[Vikram]
What a fine job, Ankush. Fabulous!
And the next skater is from Delhi...
Rahul, take this quickly.
Tipu, hurry up. Let's run.
We're getting late for the wedding.
[bell ringing]
Ankush, why are you still wandering?
Go. Get dressed. Come on.
And is this the time to skate?
- [folk music playing]
- [people singing]
Everyone is ready outside.
The wedding procession is on its way.
[Prerna] I don't want to be weak, Ankush.
[panting]
I want to skate one last time.
Tipu, leave that.
What?
Go, quickly. I'll tell didi the plan.
What happened?
[Vikram] With Shivam,
we end our Junior Boys category.
[in English] Okay, hold this. Hang on.
[Vikram, in Hindi]
Moving to the Senior Girls category.
- In the Senior Girls category, we have...
- Vikram.
We love surprising people in this village!
So far we've given girls a preference,
but for now, we’ll let our boys go first.
Put your hands together
for the Senior Boys category.
Rahul!
He's carving his line
with great speed and focus.
[crowd cheers]
[Vikram] Well done, Rahul.
And a wonderful foot-twisting trick!
Our skate village is rocking it!
Papa, that fabric fell off.
Okay, go keep this plate inside.
You're still here?
You can't do one thing right.
- Ankush, I’ve been looking for you.
- [father] Here, take the plate.
[inspirational music playing]
[knocking on door]
[woman] Prerna, hurry!
The wedding procession is here.
[music playing]
Didi, how did you get out?
- Girls round is still left, right?
- Yeah, run away.
But how will you skate in this?
[dramatic music playing]
[priest chanting]
[whispering] Call Prerna.
Prerna?
Our next senior contestant is
Deepa from Janwar!
- [crowd cheers]
- [Vikram] Give her a round of applause.
[in English] Come on, girl! Shred it!
[dramatic music playing]
[horn honks]
[in Hindi] Where are you going?
[Vikram]
Wow. Mini is landing trick after trick.
And that's an impressive trick.
I don't even know what it's called.
Our little shredders are getting
a lot of inspiration today. Right?
Let’s hear a big round
of applause for her.
Well done, Mini. Well done!
Now what can be better than
the queen herself gracing us
with her presence?
[in English]
We have girls from our village.
[in Hindi] With a huge round of applause,
let's welcome our queen.
[crowd cheers]
[Vikram] She graciously donated her land
for this skate park.
Khempur village is privileged to have her
here at this skating competition.
We welcome you wholeheartedly,
Your Highness.
Let's hear a big round of applause.
[crowd cheers and applauds]
And our next participant is...
[girl, in English] Take my shoes.
[Vikram, in Hindi]...the last contestant
from the Senior Girls category,
and the only participant
in this category from our village...
our very own, Prerna!
[crowd cheers]
[Vikram] Let's give it up for Prerna.
[crowd cheers and applauds]
[inspirational music playing]
[Vikram] And with such ease,
she’s done the Bert slide trick.
[inspirational music continues]
[Vikram] She needs to stay on her board
for just 15 more seconds.
But one minute,
looks like Prerna is heading
towards the monster bowl!
[in English] Come on, kid.
Come on, Prerna.
[ethereal music plays]
[crowd cheering]
Whoo!
- [cheering continues]
- [Jessica] Come on!
That's my girl! Whoo!
[queen, in Hindi]
Before announcing the winners,
I'd like to say that,
for the first time,
I'm seeing such joy in this village.
If we just give our kids
that one opportunity,
maybe someday we'll find
a world champion from this village.
But a champion isn’t someone
who just wins.
A true champion is someone
who shows courage,
passion and determination
when faced with adversity.
You did an amazing drop in. Come.
[queen] And today I witnessed
that courage and determination in someone.
I would like to give that person
a special award.
[in English] Sorry, Papa.
Prerna Bhil.
[in Hindi] Come on stage.
Don’t be nervous, come.
Go.
[soft instrumental music playing]
[Ankush] Shoes!
- [Prerna laughs]
- Red color shoes!
["Shine On Me" playing]
[man vocalizing]
[woman, in English]
♪ If I can see it, I believe it's done ♪
♪ I got the power, I do what I want ♪
♪ I am the one, shine like the sun ♪
♪ Make you believe it
I'm second to none ♪
♪ Do it alone, I'll take it high
There is no limit to stars in the sky ♪
♪ Straight from the heart, ready to fight
No one can stop me, I'm gonna shine ♪
♪ There is nobody
That can stand in my way ♪
♪ The light of my life will shine today ♪
♪ Huh ♪
[in Hindi] ♪ I’ve touched the pinnacle ♪
♪ I’ve realized my worth ♪
♪ Now that my feet
Have opened up as wings ♪
♪ Why should I conform? ♪
♪ Why shouldn’t I weave
The dreams my eyes have seen? ♪
♪ The complications of my life
Have to be resolved ♪
♪ The trust I have in me has to manifest ♪
♪ I'll touch the sky, immersed in joy ♪
♪ Like the wind ♪
[in English]
♪ There's no other feeling like this ♪
♪ Oh, my feet on the ground ♪
♪ I've been searching for an answer ♪
♪ One that I think I've found, oh ♪
♪ Reaching for the sky
Every time I fall, I get back up ♪
♪ If I never try
How will I know what I'm made of? ♪
♪ There will be a time
When the sun will shine ♪
♪ Feels like today ♪
♪ Oh, oh, whoa ♪
♪ Sun is gonna shine on me ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
[in Hindi] ♪ I’ve taken flight ♪
♪ Oh ♪
[in English]
♪ I know the sun is gonna shine on me ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Yes, I can see it, my name in the sky
I got that feeling I just can't describe ♪
♪ Out of my way, I came to blow
No one can stop me, I'm in control ♪
♪ Think of a goal, get it done
No slowing down, baby, you better run ♪
♪ High or low, anytime
No one can stop you, your time to shine ♪
♪ If I never try it, I will never know ♪
♪ And I can't give up on my dreams ♪
♪ So I'mma bring the light, yeah
I'mma start a fire ♪
♪ I'm not afraid, I am free ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ No ♪
♪ Sun is gonna, sun is gonna shine on me ♪
♪ Whoa, oh ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, whoa ♪
♪ Sun is, sun is gonna shine on me ♪
[in Hindi] ♪ I've taken flight ♪
[song ends]